McCulloch, Frank Papers 5883
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series SERIES II. SUBJECT FILES
  - Labor Law Reform Study, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    Includes: Labor Law Reform Study: Amendments to the Labor Management Relations Act. Sept. 1969 Draft and Draft Working Papers, Fifth Revision, Nov. 6 1967., McCulloch's notes on the Study. *Note - The Labor Law Reform Study was prepared by the "Troika" of Guy Farmer, Gerry Reilly and Theodore Iserman. The Study received financial support from the Chamber of Commerce and the NAM
  - Labor Law Reversals (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    Includes: memoranda and listings of NLRB decisions overruling precedent, defenses against the claim that the NLRB is anti-business
  - Labor - Personnel Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Various issues from 1962-1963, Re: advice to management about unions. Published by the Research Institute of America
  - Labor Policy Association, 1958-1964 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Includes: Petro, Sylvester. How the NLRB Repealed Taft-Hartley: The Destruction of Free Employee Choice. Washington, D.C.: Labor Policy Association, 1958., Kammholz, Theophil. "Organization Drives: modern Programs for Pamphleteers." Mid-Winter Personnel Conference. American Management Association. Chicago. 14 February 1961., letter to companies requesting financial contributions to support the agency's work on compulsory arbitration - 1964 other letters, memoranda, publications, articles from the Daily Labor Report
  - Labor Relations, General, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
    includes news clippings
  - Labor Relations, General (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    late 1960s-mid 1970s; Includes: news clippings. Note - this entry overlaps with the previous entry, but the two appeared separately in McCulloch's original files and consequently are left as separate files.
  - Labor Relations, General, 1975-1980 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Includes: articles, handwritten notes, 1975. Statement of Frank McCulloch to the Special Subcommittee on Labor, Committee on Education and Labor, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C. November, various bills submitted to the House of Representatives in 1977. *Note - these are materials that were included in a later submission by Frank McCulloch and are noted to provide evidence of the need for reform in labor law
  - Labor's Community Program, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 19-22)
    Includes: Conway, Jack and Woodrow Ginsburg. "The Extension of Collective Bargaining to New Fields." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Nineteenth Annual Winter Meeting of the Industrial Relations Research Association., Looking Forward - a series of occasional papers published by the League for Industrial Democracy., "Watts Labor Community Action Committee" Unpublished Report. Los Angeles: Watts Labor Community Action Committee, 1967., other reports re: similar goals and interests of labor and the Civil Rights Movement, community and social programs, community unions, program, notes and preparatory materials for a speech delivered by Frank McCulloch for the Cleveland Park Congregational United Church of Christ's Seminar on the Urban Crisis (1968) re: labor unions, press releases of the AFL-CIO, news clippings, magazines, newsletters
  - Legislation - Agricultural Employment and the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA), 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 23-25)
    Includes: various bills from 1971 - HR 1597, HR 1410, HR 5281, HR 1598, HR 1691, HR 1689, S 1866, statements of Ogden Fields, Executive Secretary of the National Labor Relations Board - 1967. S. 8. Statement before the Subcommittee on Migratory Labor Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Washington, D.C. July 13 and 1967. HR 4769. Statement before the Special Subcommittee on Labor, House Committee on Education and Labor, Washington, D.C. May 8., correspondence, reports re: extension of NLRA to agriculture
  - Legislation - Emergency Public Interest Protection (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Includes. S. 3526. S. 594 Congressional Record, memoranda, papers for discussion, news articles
  - Legislation - General, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
    Includes: S. 1890, S 3456, S. 3452-3456 (Javit's Bills), HR 11725, S. 2226, S. 2133, Section 907 of Departments of Labor and Health Education and Welfare Appropriations Act (Broyhill or Hobson Amendments), amendments to sections 206-214 of Title II of the Labor Management Relations Act of 1947, Federal Mediation and Conciliatory Services (FMCS) proposed revisions to sections 201-205 of Title II of the Labor Management Relations Act, draft of Section 14(b) NLRA testimony. Also includes: reports, memoranda, correspondence related to these legislative documents
  - Legislation - Legal Services Corporation, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Includes: Congressional Record with statement by Senator Walter Mondale re: S. 1305; press release from the White House re: Office of Economic Opportunity; S. 1305, HR 8163, HR 6360
  - Legislation - Postal Service Bill., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    Includes: "Postal Reorganization and Salary Adjustment Act of 1970" report to accompany HR 17070, HR 15430 - Dec 1969, handwritten notes, news articles
  - Limitations on Congressional Inquiry - Pillsbury Case (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Includes: memorandum re: preparation for Ervin Subcommittee Hearings
  - Lockouts (Box 10, Folder 32-34)
    Includes: Supreme Court Cases - The American Shipbuilding Company v. National Labor Relations Board, National Labor Relations Board v. John Brown et al., Circuit Court of Appeals cases, papers presented at law conferences, handwritten notes, memoranda re: relevant cases
  - Major Labor Law Principles Established by the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1961-1970 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    Includes BNA reports, summaries
  - Miscellaneous Issues Faced by the NLRB., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    Includes issues such as: forcing employer confessions to violations of the NLRA, employer unfair labor practices, scare tactics, White House intervention in changes to election rules. Some Aspects of the Union's Duty of Fair Representation by Benjamin Aaron. Reprinted from a symposium on Internal Union Affairs in the Ohio State Law Journal, Winter. Institute of Industrial Relations, University of California, Los Angeles, CA. Reprint No. 98., relations between the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) and the American Bar Association
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1949-1967 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    Includes: Wirtz, Willard. "Education and Labor." Twentieth Anniversary Labor Education Division. Roosevelt University Commencement Address. Remarks by: Rolf Weil, Edward Sparling, and Frank McCulloch. 9 Feb. 1967. Scher, Seymour. "Regulatory Agency Control Through Appointment: The Case of the Eisenhower Administration and the NLRB." The Journal of Politics 23 (1961)): 667-688. The Research and Policy Committee of the Committee For Economic Development. Union Powers and Union Functions: Toward a Better Balance. A Statement on National Policy. March 1964. "The Useless Paper Company and the Paper Shufflers Union," Mock decision prepared by Paul Herzog to read at the Omaha Regional Conference, December 1, 1949., "The NLRB Coloring Book," definition of "expertise"
  - National Association of Manufacturers (NAM) (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
    Includes: statement for the 1968 Platform Committee of the Republican Party (7/29/68), Blue Ribbon Committee pamphlets and various other pamphlets, NAM reports, conference materials
  - National Labor-Management Foundation (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Includes: pamphlets, press releases, position statements - early 1970s
  - NLRA Repeat Violators (Box 11, Folder 8-10)
    Includes materials re: most frequent violators, potential remedies - denial of government contracts, JP Stevens and co.
  - NLRB Activity - "Dotson Upheaval", 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 11-16)
    Includes: news articles, correspondence, handwritten notes
  - NLRB - Addresses given by Board members (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Includes address given by Guy Farmer, Frank McCulloch, and William Rodgers re: administering labor law
  - NLRB and Business (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
    Includes: news and journal articles, handwritten notes, statements of policy, correspondence, handwritten notes. See also: Chamber of Commerce and National Association of Manufacturers (NAM) files
  - NLRB - Data, Statistics, Tables, Reports, 1948-1969 (Box 11, Folder 20-36)
    Re: caseloads, remedies, administration of the law, types of cases, annual reports, summary of operations - mid 1960s- mid 1970s, general council summaries
  - NLRB Delegation to the General Counsel (Box 11, Folder 37)
    Includes: Memorandum of Understanding between the Board and the General Counsel, statements of the authority and responsibilities of the general counsel
  - NLRB History, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    Includes: tributes to Judge J. Warren Madden - first Chairman of the NLRB, address by J. Warren Madden, correspondence
  - NLRB Operations, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    Includes: various reports - "Current NLRB Operations," "New Directions at the National Labor Relations Board," and "Summary of Operations for the Office of the General Counsel for Fiscal Year 1984"
  - NLRB Reform - Neutral and pro-NLRB articles, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 40-42)
    Includes: News articles comments on NLRB memos
  - NLRB Response to proposals to revise the NLRA, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    Includes: drafts of Gerald Brown's speech, statement of Senator Wayne Morse - 1968. Attempt by Some Special Interest Groups to Rewrite the National Labor Relations Act. Statement before the U.S. Senate, Washington, D.C. August 2. By Senator Wayne Morse
  - NLRB State Labor Boards, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    Includes: Parker, Hyman. "Summary of Remarks and Comments by Participants" From the Conference of the National Labor Relations Board, General Counsel and State Agency Representatives. Washington, D.C. Jan 26, 1965., memoranda, correspondence among several Chairmen of the National Association of State Labor Relations Agencies, statistics, case summaries
  - NLRB Task Force, 1975-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    Includes: speeches by John Fanning at various conference, news articles
  - Neutrals (Box 12, Folder 4)
    listings of names
  - New York University 17th Annual Conference on Labor, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    Includes: MacCulloch, Frank. "The Consequences of NLRB Action on Good Faith Bargaining." 17th Annual Conference on Labor. New York University School of Law the Barbizon-Plaza Hotel, New York. 27 May 1964., correspondence, details about the conference
  - Pre-1961 Proposed Amendments to the National Labor Relations Act, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    Includes: Committee Prints and Congressional Conference Reports, Finley, Joseph. Understanding the 1959 Labor Law. Public affairs Institute: Washington, 1960., Congressional Record, outline of changes made in the Landrum-Griffin Act
  - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Includes: general news articles
  - Presidential Campaign - Proposed NLRA Reforms and the NLRB Response, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    Includes: overviews of Republican platform, confidential memos, plans, handwritten notes
  - Program Suggestions - Request of President Lyndon Johnson, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
    Includes: statement and letter from President Johnson (1964) asking all agency heads to submit five program suggestions, Frank McCulloch's suggestions for changes in the labor law; Hearing before Subcommittee on Lab of the House of Representatives re: Extension of the NLRA to agricultural workers memoranda
  - Proposal to Create Regional Boards (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Includes: proposal written by Ogden Fields, S.2135 "An Act to Authorize the Securities and Exchange Commission to Delegate Certain Functions" (7/26/62)
  - Proposals for Changes in the Law (National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) and Administrative Procedures act (APA)), 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 16-19)
    Includes: Thompson Special Subcommittee on Labor information, inquiry from and reply to Senator Edward Long, McCord, Robert and Daniel Pollitt. "Proposals For Change." A Preliminary Report to Chairman Frank Thompson, Jr. December 1965., IUD Conference, Griffin Bill (HR 11217), Thompson-O'Hara Rebuttals 1962, Norton Come memo re: APA, remarks of Representative O'Hara, Representative Landrum and Representative Griffin in the Congressional Record, 1962-63 re: the NLRB and Congressional Intent
  - Prospects for Labor Law, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Includes: news articles from 1967-1970
  - Racial Discrimination (as related to unfair labor practices and certification elections) (Box 12, Folder 21-30)
    Includes: Correspondence, case citations, text of Supreme Court cases, press releases, news articles, Congressional Record, "Race-Hate Propaganda in NLRB Representation Elections" Memorandum by Daniel Pollit, memoranda, correspondence and reports re: Equal Employment Opportunity (requests from the President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity)
  - Racial Discrimination - Complaint Statistics., 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    Fiscal years 1967 and 1968. From the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission
  - Reader's Digest - Reaction to August 1968 article "Let's Enfore Our Labor Laws Fairly" (Box 12, Folder 32-33)
    Includes: text of article, statements before the Ervin Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers, memoranda
  - Reappointment - Brown, Gerald A., 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 34-35)
    Includes: letters of endorsement, opopsition from the Chamber of Commerce, letters, meeting agendas, transcript of nomination hearings, McCulloch's handwritten notes, press releases
  - Reappointment - Ordman, Arnold (Box 12, Folder 36-37)
    Includes: handwritten notes, letters in support of Ordman as General Counsel, other correspondence
  - Reappointment - Jenkins, Howard., 1973 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    Includes: Letter from Chairman Edward Miller to the President of the United States August 31 1973 re: poor handling of Jenkins' reappointment
  - Rebuttal to Nation's Business, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    Includes: Wingo, Walter. "Roots of Union Power, part two: How government fattens unions." Nation's Business (September 1967): 70-78., Wingo, Walter. "Roots of Union Power, part three: How labor laws could be reformed." Nation's Business (October 1967): 104-111., letter to Senator Edward Kennedy from Associate Executive Secretary John Truesdale
  - Regional Conferences, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: memoranda with information on training conferences and on workshop reports and reports of workshop chairmen
  - Remedies (Box 13, Folder 3-13)
    Includes: correspondence with the department of Justice re: using Civil Rights Statute as a legal remedy against third party efforts to block organizing, cases, analyses, reports
  - Remedies - Aspin Study, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Includes: A study of Reinstatement Under the National Labor Relations Act. Study submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements of the degree of Doctor of Philosophy, Department of Economics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  - Remedies - Compensatory Remedies (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
    Includes: cases from the Supreme Court of Ontario, cases before the Ontario Labor Relations Board and a case before the Supreme Court of the State of California.
  - Remedies - Ex-Cell-O Drafts, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 18-20)
    Includes: drafts of the opinions of members of the National Labor Relations Board in the Ex-Cell-O corporation case
  - Remedies - Ex-Cell-O - Zinke - Oral Arguments (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
    Includes: reports on problems with the implementation of the proposed Ex-Cell-O - Zinke remedy, drafts of decisions
  - Remedies - Internal, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 24-27)
    Includes: "National Labor Relations Board Justifications of Appropriation Estimates - Fiscal Year 1975" for the Committee on Appropriations., Aspin, Leslie. "Digest of 'A Study of Reinstatement Under the National Labor Relations Act'", 1966, "Proposed modification of Reinstatement Remedy to require respondents to report to Regional Director concerning treatment of discriminates after reinstatement" - memorandum prepared by Harry Brickman to meet request of members of the NLRB., summary and analysis of Philip Ross's study, "Improving the Effectiveness of the Duty to Bargain," memos re: reinstatement remedies, Ex-Cell-O case, Albemarle case, other cases
  - Remedies and "Reform" - NLRB., 1975 (Box 13, Folder 28-30)
    Includes: reports on the need to strengthen remedies (prepared by Brickman), summary of Ross studies and others on the effects of NLRB actions, Chamber of Commerce Reform Proposal, 1975 statements before the House Labor Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations - Frank McCulloch, Edward Miller, Stephen Schlossberg (General Counsel of the International Union, UAW.)
  - Reorganization Plan 5, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1-9)
    Includes: notes for various parts of the plan, tabulations of votes in the House of Representatives and the Senate on reorganization plan. Support of Reorganization Plan No. 5. Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Executive and Legislative Reorganization Subcommittee of the Committee on Government Operations, House of Representatives., actual text and drafts of Reorganization Plan No. 5, Congressional Record, journal articles, reports, handwritten notes, correspondence, memoranda
  - Reorganization Plan 5 - mid to late 1960s, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
    Includes: United States. Cong. House. National Labor Relations Act Remedies: The Unfulfilled Promise. 90th Cong., 2nd sess. Committee Print. Washington: GPO 1968., draft of proposed bill to amend section 10 of the National Labor Relations Act, annual report of 1969 administrative conference, other drafts of the reorganization plans, correspondence
  - Reorganization Plan 5 - Contributions from Bar Associations, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Includes: proposals from the Association of the Bar of the City of New York and the Federal Bar Council
  - Requests for 10(j) Relief, 1961-1964 (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    Includes: Summary of requests prepared for the Board by General Counsel Arnold Ordman, memoranda
  - Research of the NLRB, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 17-19)
    Includes: proposals, contacts, various reports and studies conducted by university faculty and others, correspondence
  - Research - Suggested Topics, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Includes: letter to President Lyndon Johnson containing five program suggestions, report prepared by Harry Brickman re: research possibilities in labor-management relations
  - Rule Making, 1964-1971 (Box 14, Folder 21-23)
    Includes: Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. Major Labor Law Principles Established by the NLRB and the Courts, December 1964-February 1971. Washington: Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., 1971., speeches and statements before Congress by Frank McCulloch and Arnold Ordman, correspondence with Judge Henry Friendly of the U.S. Court of Appeals, cases, press releases
  - Rule Making vs. Adjudication (Box 14, Folder 24)
    Includes: statistics, reports, handwritten notes, correspondence
  - Rule Making - Model Cards, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
    Includes: reports of Committee on Model Cards, Williams, Jerre. "The NLRB and Administrative Rulemaking." Administrative Conference of the United States. The Southwestern Legal Foundation. Dallas. 31 Oct. 1969., case before the 5th Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals - NLRB vs. Southland Paint Company, Inc., drafts of the card, handwritten notes, correspondence, memoranda re: Administrative Procedure Act, rule making.
  - Rule Making - NLRB Jurisdiction (Box 14, Folder 28)
    Includes: press releases, NLRB jurisdictional guide re: private colleges and universities, private pre-schools, elementary and secondary schools, symphony orchestras, horse racing and dog racing
  - Rutledge, Ivan - Special Consultant to the NLRB Chairman. (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
    Includes: agendas for luncheon meetings, reports and studies of issues facing the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), press releases, insights from Daniel Pollitt - outgoing Special Consultant
  - Shultz Confirmation Hearings, 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Includes: Consideration of the Nomination of George P. Shultz to be Secretary of Labor. Transcript of Hearings before the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, US Senate, Washington, D.C. January 1966. Review of the National Labor Relations Act. Hearing before the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the Committee on Education and Labor, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C. February and September., memorandum
  - Statements Before the House of Representatives, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    Includes: full text of statements made by Frank McCulloch, Stephen Schlossberg and the US Chamber of Commerce, pending legislation and bills, background materials
  - Thompson Special Subcommittee on Labor (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
    Includes: statements of Frank McCulloch, Arnold Ordman, John Fanning, and Edward Miller before the Subcommittee re: HR 7152. Also includes: S. 1320, S. 1844 and S. 1780, articles and statements re: speech limitations and authorization cards, especially in NLRB v. Gissel Packing Company, Inc.
  - Tower Bill - S. 3671 (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    Includes: text of the Tower Bill, statements of Edward Miller, Arnold Ordman, Stephen Schlossberg, Thomas E. Harris before the Senate Subcommittee on Separation of Powers re: S. 3671, Millers drafts and requests for input from Frank McCulloch
  - Trial Examiners - Civil Service Commission Advisory Committee (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Includes: portions of the Administrative Procedures Act, meeting minutes, Rules and Regulations excerpted from the Federal Register, announcement of examination for hearing examiner positions
  - Trial Examiners - Role in Settlements (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
    Includes: memoranda, studies, reports, press releases
  - Trial Examiner Selection (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    Includes: press releases, statistics, correspondence, hand-written notes, memoranda, reports and analyses
  - Trial Examiner Selective Certification Controversy, 1960-1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Administration Conference of the United States, Statement of George Bokat in Behalf of Frank W. McCulloch, before the Committee on Personnel, Washington, D.C. April 1960. Selective Certification Method of Appointing Hearing Examiners. Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on Government Operations, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C. August., summary of remarks to the Advisory Committee on Hearing Examiners, statistics, correspondence
  - Twenty-Five Millionth Voter Celebration, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 16-20)
    Includes: speeches and remarks from the day of the celebration (March 2, 1967), correspondence, press releases, memoranda, Congressional Record, see also: photos
  - Union Resistance to the NLRB, 1963-1968 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Includes: newsletters, news articles, correspondence
  - Vacancies on the NLRB - Prospective Nominees (Box 15, Folder 22-23)
    Includes: biographical statements and summaries, correspondence, letters of recommendation
  - Whitman Case Study of Seniority (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Series SERIES III: SPEECHES AND TESTIMONIES
  - Sub-Series A: Speeches By Frank McCulloch
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The National Labor Relations Act at Age 35: Some Comments on the Law and the Changing Labor Relations Scene.", 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      25th Anniversary of the Industrial Relations Center of the University of Minnesota. Minnesota
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Administrative Procedures of Regulatory Agencies.", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Unpublished Paper (?) June 1969